Maxime St-Onge Amoretti

Backend Software Developer

💌 maxime.stongea@gmail.com 💡 Toronto, Canada 🙎 English, French, Spanish 🤘 maxamoretti.com

PROFILE

I am a strong independent problem solver who loves contributing to vibrant teams. After spending three years working as an actuarial associate in the insurance industry, I decided to re-skill in May 2022 to become a software developer.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Co-Creator, Software Developer

Jan 2023 - Apr 2023

Otter (otter-framework.dev) *⊘*

Otter is a cloud native framework to easily integrate peer-to-peer video communication within web applications.

- Engineered an auto-scaling serverless infrastructure on AWS to enable WebRTC functionality into web applications (HTTP/WebSocket API Gateways, Lambda functions, ECS with Fargate, and DynamoDB).
- Wrote a CLI tool to automate the provisioning and teardown of AWS cloud infrastructure (AWS CLI).
- Developed a frontend application for private 1-on-1 meetings hosted by Otter (CloudFront with S3 Bucket). Features include low latency audio/video communication, instant messaging, and file sharing.
- Containerized and deployed CoTURN, an open-source implementation of STUN/TURN protocols, in an ECS cluster with Fargate to support Otter's P2P connectivity.
- Built a simple API for developers to integrate Otter's functionality within their web applications.
- Secured HTTP/WebSocket API Gateways by using an API key and JSON Web Tokens.
- Optimized Otter for low latency by reducing the number of reads to DynamoDB.
- Authored a technical case study on the design decisions and engineering challenges faced while building Otter.

Launch School

Attended a mastery-based education program focused on software engineering fundamentals.

- ReAck: An application for collecting and inspecting HTTP webhook requests. ReAck is built with React, Node.js (Express framework), PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and Nginx.
- Rate Your Dinner: An application for rating culinary experiences. Built with Pug templating engine, Node. is and PostgreSQL.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Actuarial Analyst, Actuarial Services - Consulting

Sep 2021 – Apr 2022 | Toronto

RSM Canada

• Performed the valuation of multiple insurance companies at year-end.

Actuarial Analyst, Corporate Reserving

Feb 2021 – Aug 2021 | Toronto

Northbridge Financial Corporation

• Prepared the valuation of the commercial lines of business cumulating to more than \$1 billion.

Actuarial Analyst II, Actuarial Pricing

Jun 2020 – Feb 2021 | Toronto

Wawanesa Insurance

• Analyzed and monitored multiple insurance products on a monthly basis.

Actuarial Analyst, P&C Actuarial Practice - Consulting

Jan 2019 – Jun 2020 | Toronto

KPMG Canada

Participated in the audit of over 20 clients during year-ends and contributed to Appointed Actuary work.

SKILLS

Frontend	Backend	Other
JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS	Node.js, Go, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful APIs	TypeScript, WebRTC, Docker, Nginx, Git, AWS (Lambda, ECS, EC2, Fargate,
		API Gateway CloudFront S3 NLB)

EDUCATION

Software Engineering & Full-Stack Web Development

2022

Launch School

B.Sc. - Mathematics (Actuarial Specialization)

2018